Ilya Biin

Senior Software Engineer

One Rockwell East Tower, 1210, Makati, Metro Manila PH

in ilyabiin O biinilya



Ilya has more than a decade's worth of experience working as a system architect, a Go developer, and DevOps. He has implemented various AWS works (integration, price optimization, and high availability), automation setup, and orchestration. Overall, Ilya is a professional developer with a good knowledge of APIs and security.

SKILLS -

Backend			DevOps			Databases				
	golang	pythor	c/c++		ci/cd	docker	kubernetes	postgres	redis	aerospike
	c10k problem nat traversal		rsal	aws	ansible	prometheus	elasticsearch			
	tcp strea	am mult	iplexing							

WORK EXPERIENCE (6)

Software Engineer at Ferrum Health Inc. November 2018- Current

Ferrum Health Inc. is an AI company focused on X-Rays pictures analysis. This position was opened to help them in building metrics/logging/analytics system.

- The system was designed. Stack used: ElasticSearch/Kibana/Logbeats/Metricbeat/Heartbeat/Wazuh
- On-premise datacenter environment deployment supported as well as replication to AWS-based ElasticSearch
- System setup, dependencies, and management documented
- Metrics Framework integrated into existing products

Software Developer at Coins.ph December 2017- October 2018

Coins.ph is a digital wallet that Filipinos can use to make payments or buy digital currency such as Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, and Ethereum. As a Software Developer, I was a part of the infrastructure team.

- Alphapoint exchange integrated, providing the customers with an inexpensive way to exchange fiat and crypto-currencies
- Golang micro-service template designed
- Postgres performance issues resolved
- Integrated Prometheus monitoring to Kubernetes cluster and the apps running in it
- Redis cluster autoscaling for Kubernetes

Software Engineer at Gett.com February 2017- December 2017

Gett is a taxi app, like Uber, that's most popular in Russia and Israel. As a part of a Billing Team, I was responsible for delivering internal accounting service for drivers and passengers.

- Prepared the team to pass an internal qualification test based on Go
- Crafted the architecture of the driver earnings service (DES) with an embedded conflict resolution system
- Developed an API for the business intelligence in the driver earnings service (DES).
- Resolved the load issue in the DES production

System Architect at Emerging Travel Inc. (ETI) February 2015- October 2016

Active engagement in the development of middle and long-term tech strategy. Maintaining high availability of a project. Research and development of scalable project architecture. Splitting monolith code blocks into individual services. Providing developer teams with convenient tools and services for every-day tasks. Resolving technical questions with partners.

- A pipeline of third-parties integrations
- Micro-service architecture on top of Kubernetes

Network balancing layer

Software Engineer at Emerging Travel Inc. (ETI) October 2011- February 2015

Website search system speed and quality improvements.

- Dynamic pricing engine (based on marketing, supply, and customer properties)
- Business rules engine
- Splitting monolith python code to Golang/Python microservices
- 1Tb/100,000rps caching layer, based on Aerospike cluster

Software Developer at Mail.Ru Group February 2010- October 2011

- ICQ (AOL) acceptance tests (when it was bought by the Mail.RU Group)
- Developed the ICQ-to-Mail.Ru Agent interservice communication (interop)

EDUCATION (2)

Bachelor of Science Computer Science at Colegio De Porta Vaga **2014 - 2018**

Bachelor of Science Applied Mathematics at Moscow Institue of Physics and Technology (MIPT) **2005 - 2009**

PUBLICATIONS

Rapid Web Development. Golang vs Ruby in Sphere Inc 28 October 2017

1,000,000 concurrent data streams in Avito Tech 28 October 2017

Golang strengths and weakness for startup in Yandex Tech talks 20 November 2013

Building a distributed cache system in PyCon Russia 2013 **24 February 2013**